<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-25T20:47:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Archive: Genetics</title><subtitle>This site serves as an archive of my PhD research in Baylor College of Medicine, mainly focusing on human Mendelian genetics.</subtitle><author><name>Mingchu Xu</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Genetics Grind</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/18/hello-hydeout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Genetics Grind" /><published>2017-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/18/hello-hydeout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/18/hello-hydeout.html">&lt;p&gt;Mingchu Xu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Genetics Grind&lt;/em&gt; is an awkward imitation of the well-known &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pgbovine.net/PhD-memoir/pguo-PhD-grind.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The PhD Grind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Dr. Philip J. Guo. Here, I set the post date as Aug 18th, 2017, the last date of my Ph.D. career for a ritual purpose, while I actually started writing these texts in April 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time of my graduation year (2017) elapsed so fast that there is almost no time left for the reflection of my Ph.D. journey, especially I was in the euphoria during the summer months of that year. After a long ordeal of postdoctoral life in San Diego and unsuccessful job searches, I moved back to Houston and finally managed to secure a position in University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. Waiting for my final appointment to the new job, I decided that it’s the time for writing something, which I called an archive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important source for the accuracy of this archive is that I have kept all the emails (certainly including all the attachments) since Apr 25th, 2013. Unfortunately, I am not able to retrieve emails before that date, leading to the loss of the information on how things unfolded during my three rotations terms, as well as the events occurred at the first two months I’ve spent in the lab. Nevertheless, I feel confident to present the remaining 95% here. Importantly, I plan to cite many (if not most) original email texts here for explaining the situations I’ve encountered and serving the critical goal of this archive, the &lt;strong&gt;historical accuracy&lt;/strong&gt;. Moreover, I would try making my narration as objective as possible, and hopefully, certain complex scenarios would not become the Rashomon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ch1&quot;&gt;I. Fresh Off the Boat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;ch1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;I &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Fresh Off the Boat&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 11:23 a.m., Jul 1st, 2013, I emailed my Curriculum Vitae (CV), which is due on the same day, to Ms. Judith Coleman (Judi), the coordinator of the graduate program. By that day, I was approaching the end of my first year in Baylor College of Medicine, and have finished most of the coursework. In the &lt;em&gt;current work in progress&lt;/em&gt; section of the CV, I listed two projects:
&lt;a name=&quot;fno1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Identifying the pathogenic property of LRP6&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; D735N mutation in patients with ocular and developmental defects &lt;a name=&quot;fno2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Neuroprotective role of NMNAT1&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; protein in mouse retina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are indeed two important projects during my first year: the &lt;em&gt;LRP6&lt;/em&gt; story started on Jan 2nd, 2013, exactly the first day of my rotation and the first business day of that year (if research can also be regarded as certain type of business), while I also started the NMNAT1 project as proposed by my mentor, Dr. Rui Chen (Rui) in late February. My performance in the former project probably contributed a lot to my final acceptance into the lab, and the latter represented one of Rui’s &lt;strong&gt;brilliant&lt;/strong&gt; ideas, which we later dubbed elixir (&lt;em&gt;Chinese&lt;/em&gt;: 万能药).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I didn't use the italic &lt;i&gt;LRP6&lt;/i&gt; for human gene name in my original CV. This is just another piece of evidence showing my inexperience in the genetics field at that time. &lt;a href=&quot;#fno1&quot;&gt;&amp;larr;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;fn2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Similarly, all-capital non-italic already indicates the human/mouse protein. &lt;a href=&quot;#fno2&quot;&gt;&amp;larr;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/font&gt;</content><author><name>Mingchu Xu</name></author><summary type="html">Mingchu Xu The Genetics Grind is an awkward imitation of the well-known The PhD Grind by Dr. Philip J. Guo. Here, I set the post date as Aug 18th, 2017, the last date of my Ph.D. career for a ritual purpose, while I actually started writing these texts in April 2018. The time of my graduation year (2017) elapsed so fast that there is almost no time left for the reflection of my Ph.D. journey, especially I was in the euphoria during the summer months of that year. After a long ordeal of postdoctoral life in San Diego and unsuccessful job searches, I moved back to Houston and finally managed to secure a position in University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center. Waiting for my final appointment to the new job, I decided that it’s the time for writing something, which I called an archive. One important source for the accuracy of this archive is that I have kept all the emails (certainly including all the attachments) since Apr 25th, 2013. Unfortunately, I am not able to retrieve emails before that date, leading to the loss of the information on how things unfolded during my three rotations terms, as well as the events occurred at the first two months I’ve spent in the lab. Nevertheless, I feel confident to present the remaining 95% here. Importantly, I plan to cite many (if not most) original email texts here for explaining the situations I’ve encountered and serving the critical goal of this archive, the historical accuracy. Moreover, I would try making my narration as objective as possible, and hopefully, certain complex scenarios would not become the Rashomon. Table of Contents I. Fresh Off the Boat I &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Fresh Off the Boat At 11:23 a.m., Jul 1st, 2013, I emailed my Curriculum Vitae (CV), which is due on the same day, to Ms. Judith Coleman (Judi), the coordinator of the graduate program. By that day, I was approaching the end of my first year in Baylor College of Medicine, and have finished most of the coursework. In the current work in progress section of the CV, I listed two projects: Identifying the pathogenic property of LRP61 D735N mutation in patients with ocular and developmental defects Neuroprotective role of NMNAT12 protein in mouse retina These are indeed two important projects during my first year: the LRP6 story started on Jan 2nd, 2013, exactly the first day of my rotation and the first business day of that year (if research can also be regarded as certain type of business), while I also started the NMNAT1 project as proposed by my mentor, Dr. Rui Chen (Rui) in late February. My performance in the former project probably contributed a lot to my final acceptance into the lab, and the latter represented one of Rui’s brilliant ideas, which we later dubbed elixir (Chinese: 万能药). 1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; I didn't use the italic LRP6 for human gene name in my original CV. This is just another piece of evidence showing my inexperience in the genetics field at that time. &amp;larr; 2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Similarly, all-capital non-italic already indicates the human/mouse protein. &amp;larr;</summary></entry></feed>