<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-24T15:40:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Archive: Genetics</title><subtitle>This site serves as an archive of my PhD research in Baylor College of Medicine, mainly focusing on human Mendelian genetics.</subtitle><author><name>Mingchu Xu</name></author><entry><title type="html">The Genetics Grind</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/18/hello-hydeout.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Genetics Grind" /><published>2017-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-08-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/18/hello-hydeout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/18/hello-hydeout.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Genetics Grind&lt;/em&gt; is an awkward imitation of the well-known &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pgbovine.net/PhD-memoir/pguo-PhD-grind.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The PhD Grind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Philip J. Guo. Here, I set the post date as Aug 18th 2017, the last date of my PhD career for a ritual purpose, while I actually started writing these texts in April 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;中文试验&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;副标题&quot;&gt;副标题&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In keeping with the original Hyde theme, Hydeout aims to keep the overall
design lightweight and plugin-free. JavaScript is currently limited only
to Disqus and Google Analytics (and is only loaded if you provide configuration
variables).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hydeout makes heavy use of Flexbox in its CSS. If Flexbox is not available,
the CSS degrades into a single column layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;customization&quot;&gt;Customization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hydeout replaces Hyde’s class-based theming with the use
of the following SASS variables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-scss highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sidebar-bg-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mh&quot;&gt;#202020&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$sidebar-sticky&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$layout-reverse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;bp&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$link-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mh&quot;&gt;#268bd2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To override these variables, create your own &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;assets/css/main.scss&lt;/code&gt; file.
Define your own variables, then import in Hydeout’s SCSS, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
# Jekyll needs front matter for SCSS files
---

$sidebar-bg-color: #ac4142;
$link-color: #ac4142;
$sidebar-sticky: false;
@import &quot;hydeout&quot;;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&quot;_sass/hydeout/_variables.scss&quot;&gt;_variables&lt;/a&gt; file for other variables
you can override.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also insert custom head tags (e.g. to load your own stylesheets) by
defining your own &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_includes/custom-head.html&lt;/code&gt; or insert tags at the end
of the body (e.g. for custom JS) by defining your own
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_includes/custom-foot.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hydeout also adds a new tags page (accessible in the sidebar) and a new
“category” layout for dedicated category pages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Category pages are automatically added to the sidebar. All other pages
must have &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sidebar_link: true&lt;/code&gt; in their front matter to show up in
the sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A simple redirect-to-Google search is available. If you want to use
Google Custom Search or Algolia or something with more involved,
override the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;search.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Disqus integration is ready out of the box. Just add the following to
your config file:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&quot;language-yaml highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;shortname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;my-disqus-shortname&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If you don’t want Disqus or want to use something else, override
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;comments.html&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Google Analytics support, define a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;google_analytics&lt;/code&gt; variable with
your property ID in your config file.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a bunch of minor tweaks and adjustments throughout the
theme. Hope this works for you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mingchu Xu</name></author><summary type="html">The Genetics Grind is an awkward imitation of the well-known The PhD Grind by Philip J. Guo. Here, I set the post date as Aug 18th 2017, the last date of my PhD career for a ritual purpose, while I actually started writing these texts in April 2018. 中文试验 副标题 In keeping with the original Hyde theme, Hydeout aims to keep the overall design lightweight and plugin-free. JavaScript is currently limited only to Disqus and Google Analytics (and is only loaded if you provide configuration variables). Hydeout makes heavy use of Flexbox in its CSS. If Flexbox is not available, the CSS degrades into a single column layout. Customization Hydeout replaces Hyde’s class-based theming with the use of the following SASS variables: $sidebar-bg-color: #202020 !default; $sidebar-sticky: true !default; $layout-reverse: false !default; $link-color: #268bd2 !default; To override these variables, create your own assets/css/main.scss file. Define your own variables, then import in Hydeout’s SCSS, like so: --- # Jekyll needs front matter for SCSS files --- $sidebar-bg-color: #ac4142; $link-color: #ac4142; $sidebar-sticky: false; @import &quot;hydeout&quot;; See the _variables file for other variables you can override. You can also insert custom head tags (e.g. to load your own stylesheets) by defining your own _includes/custom-head.html or insert tags at the end of the body (e.g. for custom JS) by defining your own _includes/custom-foot.html. New Features Hydeout also adds a new tags page (accessible in the sidebar) and a new “category” layout for dedicated category pages. Category pages are automatically added to the sidebar. All other pages must have sidebar_link: true in their front matter to show up in the sidebar. A simple redirect-to-Google search is available. If you want to use Google Custom Search or Algolia or something with more involved, override the search.html. Disqus integration is ready out of the box. Just add the following to your config file: disqus: shortname: my-disqus-shortname If you don’t want Disqus or want to use something else, override comments.html. For Google Analytics support, define a google_analytics variable with your property ID in your config file. There’s also a bunch of minor tweaks and adjustments throughout the theme. Hope this works for you!</summary></entry></feed>